Have you ever had a really big secret?
Big is a fantasy, drama, comedy film directed by Penny Marshall.
When a young boy makes a wish at a carnival machine to be big—he wakes up the following
morning to find that it has been granted and his body has grown older overnight.
But he is still the same 13-year-old boy inside.
Now he must learn how to cope with the unfamiliar world of grown-ups including
getting a job and having his first romantic encounter with a woman.
Josh Baskin, played by Tom Hanks.
Susan, played by Elizabeth Perkins.
MacMillan, played by Robert Loggia.
Paul, played by John Heard.
Billy, played by Jared Rushton.
Young Josh, played by David Moscow.
Big is a 1988 American fantasy comedy film directed by Penny Marshall and starring Tom Hanks as Josh
Baskin, an adolescent boy whose wish to be "big" transforms him physically into an adult.
The film also stars Elizabeth Perkins, David Moscow, John Heard, and Robert
Loggia, and was written by Gary Ross and Anne Spielberg.
It was produced by Gracie Films and distributed by 20th Century Fox.
Upon release, Big was met with wide critical acclaim,
particularly for Hanks' performance.
It was a huge commercial success as well, grossing $151 million worldwide against a production budget of $18 million, and it
proved to be pivotal to Hanks' career, establishing him as a major box-office draw as well as a critical favorite.
The film received Academy Award nominations for Best
Actor (Hanks) and Best Original Screenplay.
The film explores themes of baseball, coming of age, best
friend, co-workers relationship, body-swap.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.